I didn't think I would be waking up to
abject biological horror today but here
we are the brain organoids the tiny
human brains that we can grow in jars
have been released for commercial
processing access if you're not familiar
with these guys they are human brains
that have been grown from stem cells and
they have brain waves very similar to a
premature babies I am not kidding the
limitations on their use and their
growth seems to be hypoxia due to the
fact that they're a disembodied brain
and don't have a circulatory system they
can be attached to a computer chip and
have better processing power than our
most advanced AI a Swiss company neurop
platform is debuting their biological
computer chips and giving access to
private citizens to use the processing
power of the brain organoids while there
are 16 brain organoids to a chip they're
maintaining thousands of them they also
have mouse and rat brain organoids but
they explicitly use human brain
organoids there have been some
advancements in being able to keep them
alive longer including keeping them in a
media that's oxygen rich and shaking
them they live about 100 days so they
will constantly need to be refreshed as
for the company you personally can get
access to their computation it is going
to run you about $500 a month if you're
in education I am frustrated this is
brand new technology it is pretty spooky
those are functional little eyes that
can perceive light they are immature
human brains they have all the
structures that a human brain should
have they're just never reached that
point in development because you know
the lack of a circulatory system but
scientists are doing their very best to
make them bigger and more complex at
what point are we going to bring ethics
into the equation